<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sylvain Argentieri</title>
    <link>https://my.sylar.org/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://my.sylar.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Sylvain Argentieri</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://my.sylar.org/images/icon_hu1a01b3fab95c353a9499cb6a8a91062a_16677_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Sylvain Argentieri</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Formal Account of Structuring Motor Actions With Sensory Prediction for a Naive Agent</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2020j_a_formal_account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2020j_a_formal_account/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural cues characterization</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/binaural_cues_characterization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/binaural_cues_characterization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/project/robot_audition/&#34;&gt;&amp;laquo; back to Robot Audition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone agree on the physical meaning of interaural cues used for horizontal sound source localization (time delay/phase difference and amplitude difference between the left and right ears signals), there is no clear agreement on the best way to estimate their value. For instance, here is short, clearly incomplete, list of the more classical estimation methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/img/projects/cues-list.png&#34; alt=&#34;The sensorimotor version of perception&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then worked during &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/authors/karim-youssef/&#34;&gt;K. Youssef&lt;/a&gt; PhD on the comparison between the different definitions proposed in the literature, and on the evaluation of their performances evaluated through a positional classes separation criterion (in azimuth and distance), or in terms of speaker recognition rate. These works demonstrate the robustness of amplitude-bases cues w.r.t. reverberation (ands this was of course expected!), and show that cochlear frequency decomposition outperform classical FFT-based approaches, at a time where they were the most exploited in a Robotics context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: right&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/source_localization/&#34;&gt;Binaural sound source localization &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural sound source localization</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/source_localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/source_localization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/project/robot_audition/&#34;&gt;&amp;laquo; back to Robot Audition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the basis on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/binaural_cues_characterization/&#34;&gt;binaural cues characterization&lt;/a&gt;, we exploited an artificial neural network (ANN) to learn and estimate the azimuth and distance of sound sources in the environment. But realistic robotics applications involve dynamic scenarios, where the relative position between the sources and the robot can evolve along time in a reverberant environment. We have then characterized &amp;mdash;during &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/authors/karim-youssef/&#34;&gt;K. Youssef&lt;/a&gt; PhD thesis&amp;mdash; the consequences of those changes in relative and absolute positions during the learning and test phases, and studied the generalization capabilities of the proposed ANN. More precisely, we highlighted the sensitivity of the learning phase to acoustical conditions (changes in the reverberation time) and binaural receiver position (different positions in a room). Multiconditionnal learning is thus shown mandatory, even if collecting data in all the various required conditions is far from beaing easy, especially when dealing with a binaural receiver on a mobile robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: right&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/structuration_sensorimotor_flow/&#34;&gt;Structuration of the sensorimotor flow &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;--&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space dimension estimation</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/dimension_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/dimension_estimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/project/interactive_perception/&#34;&gt;&amp;laquo; back to Interactive Perception&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the sensorimotor paradigm, the question of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;space&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a primary tremendous issue. While &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; seems like a kind of universal, homogeneous and isotropic 3D container shared by all of us and our environment, discovering that &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; actually exists only on the basis on what is actually available &amp;ldquo;from the inside&amp;rdquo; (i.e. the sensorimotor flow) is far from being intuitive. Especially since the sensorimotor flow isn&amp;rsquo;t homogeneous, isotropic and 3D&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, is it possible to rediscover that &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; out there is a 3D space (at least from our point of view!), and that it can be characterize by 6 independent spatial variables corresponding to the 3 translations and 3 rotations we all know? This important question has already been raised by Henri Poincaré at the end of the 19th century. Philipona showed in 2008 it was possible to recover space dimensionality from the sensorimotor flow, but only from infinitesimal movements. By using non-linear dimensional estimation techniques, we have shown &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_non_linear_approach/&#34;&gt;in this paper&lt;/a&gt; that, while using realistic movements magnitudes, it was still possible to correctly estimate space dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: right&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/structuration_sensorimotor_flow/&#34;&gt;Structuration of the sensorimotor flow &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structuration of the sensorimotor flow</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/structuration_sensorimotor_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/structuration_sensorimotor_flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/project/interactive_perception/&#34;&gt;&amp;laquo; back to Interactive Perception&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having access to space dimension without any &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; and on the basis on solely the sensorimotor flow is quite interesting, but far from being the most useful knowledge for a robotics agent. Our previous works on these topics were mainly rooted on sensory differential manifold, and the results were thus still dependent to changes in the environment configurations. This is a problem, since the notion of &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; should not be dependent of what is actually in the agent environment&amp;hellip; We then tried to work on different ways to cope with these changes, first mainly &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015j_learning_agents_spatial_configuration/&#34;&gt;from intuition&lt;/a&gt;, and then &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/publication/2017j_building_sensorimotor_tactile_space/&#34;&gt;more formally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: right&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/dimension_estimation/&#34;&gt;Space dimension estimation &gt;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive perception</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/project/interactive_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 17:27:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/project/interactive_perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the existing works dealing with robot perception (and this includes my own on robot audition!) rely on the traditional, somewhat historical, following scheme (a.k.a. &lt;strong&gt;the perceive/plan/act scheme&lt;/strong&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first, the robot reads and understands its sensations on the basis on a priori models given by the engineers (for instance, auditory, camera, laser, etc. models, trying to make the bridge between the raw sensors outputs and its high level interpretation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;then, the system plan its action inside a generally well-known environment, whose characteristics are often identified beforehand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally, the action is actually performed by controlling the joints thanks to geometric/cinematic/dynamic models and controllers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/img/projects/sense-plan-act.png&#34; alt=&#34;The sense/plan/act paradigm&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This very generic approach do work pretty well! As long as your models (of the robot, its sensors, the world, etc.) do fit pretty well the reality for the given task, quite amazing results can be obtained. But being able to deal with incomplete models (&lt;em&gt;and they always are incomplete!&lt;/em&gt;), being able to face unpredictable situations where all your models can no longer apply is still a very difficult task. One solution could consist in questioning the aforementioned perception architecture. One could indeed envisage a new way to deal with perception where this ability is no longer somewhat given a priori by the designer of the system, but instead built and discovered by the robot, not from the raw sensory signals (i.e. the outputs od its sensors), but from the sensorimotor flow (i.e. the data made of the data coming from extero and/or proprioceptive sensors, and of the commands of the joints). Then, the previous architecture turns into&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/img/projects/sensorimotor-approach.png&#34; alt=&#34;The sensorimotor version of perception&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this line of research, the question of the emergence of internal representation of the robot interaction in its own environment is a central issue. It is indeed only on the basis on these representations that the robot will be able to plan and act in its environment (and not on &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; models like in previous approaches). This question is absolutely fundamental when trying to build robot with autonomy and adaptability capabilities, which are mandatory capabilities in modern application of Robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to work on those topics through the &lt;em&gt;sensorimotor contingencies theory&lt;/em&gt;, that explains that perceiving is analog to the discovering of stable relations (i.e. &lt;em&gt;contingencies&lt;/em&gt;) linking motors and sensory events. Then characterizing these invariants (that is, determining precisely &lt;strong&gt;what they are&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;what are their properties&lt;/strong&gt;) might help to investigate how internal representations built thanks to them could allow a robot to infer spatial structures without almost no a priori. For that purpose, we already tackled some of these aspects through two main contributions, mainly dealt with from a theoretical (mathematical) point of view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/dimension_estimation/&#34;&gt;space dimension estimation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/structuration_sensorimotor_flow/&#34;&gt;structuration of the sensorimotor flow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robot audition</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/project/robot_audition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 17:20:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/project/robot_audition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Blindness separate us from things but deafness from people”&lt;/em&gt; said Helen Keller, a famous American author who was the first deafblind person to obtain a Bachelor in Arts, in 1904. And indeed, being able to interpret an auditory scene from a robot is now a required capability when operating with humans, mainly interacting by speech with each others. Auditory scene analysis is a quite well-known research topic in Acoustics and Signal Processing, but considering its implication in Robotics, it is not as easy as expected to port all the already developments &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; a robot. The robotic context exhibit original constraints like embeddability, real-time, reveberations, ego-noise, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two main paradigms are currently exploited in Robotics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the one hand, &lt;strong&gt;array processing approaches&lt;/strong&gt; exploit microphones array to exploit redundant audio information to perform sound source localization, source separation, source recognition in a very efficient way. Recent developments definitely show that this is the way to go to develop an efficient audio system in Robotics;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;binaural approaches&lt;/strong&gt; try to somewhat mimic the human auditory system, at least from an external point of view (two ears, generally with two external ears). Using only two ears in a Robotics context is still a very challenging task. But while one could question the choice to restrict ourself to only two ears, this is also a unique opportunity to test auditory models of human audition, and to stress the importance of action in the hearing process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, hearing is rarely a purely static task. For instance, one often makes small head movements to disambiguate sound location, or better sound recognition. This is specifically what I have been dealing with, i.e. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;active binaural audition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. On this topic, I have mainly proposed contributions on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/binaural_cues_characterization/&#34;&gt;the characterization of binaural cues&lt;/a&gt; used for sound localization and source recognition in realistic conditions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the specific &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.sylar.org/projects-details/source_localization/&#34;&gt;sound localization&lt;/a&gt; problem,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the use of the binaural movement to better sound localization,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the building of multimodal representation of unknown environments through head movements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audition as a Trigger for Head Movements</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2020b_audition_as_a_trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2020b_audition_as_a_trigger/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do I move my sensors? Emergence of a topological representation of sensors poses from the sensorimotor flow</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2020j_where_do_i_move/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2020j_where_do_i_move/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un (petit) pas vers la perception interactive</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018_hdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018_hdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do I move my sensors? Emergence of an internal representation from the sensorimotor flow</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018w_where_do_i_move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018w_where_do_i_move/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Head Turning Modulation system: an active multimodal paradigm for intrinsically motivated exploration of unknown environments</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018j_head_turning_modulation_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018j_head_turning_modulation_system/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural Localization of Multiple Sound Sources by Non-Negative Tensor Factorization</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018j_binaural_non_negative_tensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2018j_binaural_non_negative_tensor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Sensorimotor Representation of a Naive Agent’s Tactile Space</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2017j_building_sensorimotor_tactile_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2017j_building_sensorimotor_tactile_space/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and exploiting a sensorimotor representation of a naive agent self-interaction</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2016w_building_exploiting_sensorimotor_representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2016w_building_exploiting_sensorimotor_representation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal fusion and inference using binaural audition and vision</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2016c_multimodal_fusion_and_inference_ica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2016c_multimodal_fusion_and_inference_ica/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Une brève introduction à la perception sensori-motrice en robotique</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2016j_intellectica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2016j_intellectica/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the auditory turn-to reflex on the basis of multimodal feedback loops: The Dynamic Weighting model</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015c_modulating_turn_to_reflex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015c_modulating_turn_to_reflex/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A survey on sound source localization in robotics: From binaural to array processing methods</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015j_survey_sound_source_localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015j_survey_sound_source_localization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the representation of an agent body from its sensorimotor invariants</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015w_building_representation_body/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015w_building_representation_body/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning agents spatial configuration from sensorimotor invariants</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015j_learning_agents_spatial_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2015j_learning_agents_spatial_configuration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensorimotor Learning of Sound Localization for an Autonomous Robot</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2014c_sensorimotor_learning_sound_localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2014c_sensorimotor_learning_sound_localization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A learning-based approach to robust binaural sound localization</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_learning_based_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_learning_based_approach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A spherical cross-channel algorithm for binaural sound localization</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_spherical_cross_channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_spherical_cross_channel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active speaker localization with circular likelihoods and bootstrap filtering</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_active_speaker_localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_active_speaker_localization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HRTF-based source azimuth estimation and activity detection from a binaural sensor</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_hrtf_base_source_azimuth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013c_hrtf_base_source_azimuth/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Decision System for Aircraft Faults Diagnosis Based on Classification Trees and PCA</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013b_decision_system_aircraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013b_decision_system_aircraft/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural Systems in Robotics</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013b_binaural_system_robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2013b_binaural_system_robotics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel aircraft fault diagnosis and prognosis system based on Gaussian Mixture Models</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_fault_diagnosis_system_gaussian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_fault_diagnosis_system_gaussian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A non-linear approach to space dimension perception by a naive agent</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_non_linear_approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_non_linear_approach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active binaural localization of intermittent moving sources in the presence of false measurements</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_active_binaural_localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_active_binaural_localization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a systematic study of binaural cues</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_towards_systematic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_towards_systematic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel aircraft engine fault diagnostic and prognostic system based on SVM</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_fault_diagnosis_system_svm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_fault_diagnosis_system_svm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel fault diagnosis system for aircraft based on adaboost and five subsystems with different pattern recognition methods</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_fault_diagnosis_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_fault_diagnosis_system/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aircraft fault diagnosis and decision system based on improved artificial neural networks</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_aircraft_fault_diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_aircraft_fault_diagnosis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A binaural sound source localization method using auditive cues and vision</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_auditive_cues_and_vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2012c_auditive_cues_and_vision/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal sound localization for humanoid robots based on visio-auditive learning</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2011c_multimodal_sound_localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2011c_multimodal_sound_localization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acoustic models and Kalman filtering strategies for active binaural sound localization</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2011c_acoustics_model_kalman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2011c_acoustics_model_kalman/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaches for Automatic Speaker Recognition in a Binaural Humanoid Context</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2011c_approaches_speaker_reco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2011c_approaches_speaker_reco/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural Speaker Recognition for humanoid robots</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_binaural_speaker_recognition2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_binaural_speaker_recognition2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural speaker recognition for humanoid robots</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_binaural_speaker_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_binaural_speaker_recognition/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From monaural to binaural speaker recognition for humanoid robots</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_monaural_binaural_speaker_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_monaural_binaural_speaker_recognition/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space dimension perception from the multimodal sensorimotor flow of a naive robotic agent</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_space_dimension_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010c_space_dimension_perception/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EAR Project</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010j_the_ear_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2010j_the_ear_project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker localization and speech extraction with the EAR sensor</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2009c_speaker_localization_ear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2009 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2009c_speaker_localization_ear/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadband variations of the MUSIC high-resolution method for Sound Source Localization in Robotics</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2007c_broadband_variation_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2007c_broadband_variation_music/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convex Optimization and Modal Analysis for Beamforming in Robotics : Theoretical and Implementation Issues</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2007c_convex_optimization_robotics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2007c_convex_optimization_robotics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conception d&#39;un capteur sonore pour la localisation de source en robotique mobile</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2006_phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2006_phd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modal Analysis Based Beamforming for Nearfield or Farfield Speaker Localization in Robotics</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2006c_modal_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2006 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2006c_modal_analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conception d&#39;un système de localisation de source sonore large bande par formation de voie pour des applications robotiques.</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2005c_conception_systeme_localisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2005 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2005c_conception_systeme_localisation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An experimental testbed for sound source localization with mobile robots using optimized wideband beamformers</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2005c_experimental_testbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2005 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2005c_experimental_testbed/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping Filter-Sum Beamformers for Sound Source Localization in Mobile Robotics</title>
      <link>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2005c_prototyping_filtersum_beamforming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my.sylar.org/publication/2005c_prototyping_filtersum_beamforming/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
